VUGAR MAMMADLI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER









PROFILE

Hello, my name is Vugar Mammadli. I am currently a software developer at IBM in Toronto, Canada. I studied at the University of Toronto and received Honours Bachelor of Science degree with a Specialist Program in Computer Science and a Minor Program in Mathematics. I am perfectly fluent in English, Turkish and Azerbaijan language, and have a good communication skill. I can also talk a little bit in Russian. I am highly organized, task oriented and work well in a team environment. I am the happiest person in the world when I learn and help someone to learn something new.



EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Honours Bachelor of Science (H.B.Sc.) SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018

Honours Bachelor of Science degree with a Specialist Program in Computer Science and a Minor Program in Mathematics. Full scholarship within the 'State Program on Education of Azerbaijani Youth Abroad in 2007-2015' during 2014-2018.



COMPUTER ENGINEERING SEP 2013 - MAY 2014

Full scholarship from the Bilkent Univeristy.



PRO SKILLS

HTML5 & CSS3	
Python	
Java	
Git / Github	
Wordpress	
Bootstrap	
JavaScript	
JQuery	
SQL	
AngularJS	
LESS	
C#	
MongoDB	
С	
Node.js	
ASP.NET	
PHP	
React Native	



WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

JULY 2018 - PRESENT

Development of new features, product maintainance and full customer support for Db2 pureScale product.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER //INTERNSHIP

JULY 2016 - AUG 2016

BAKCELL LLC

IBM

Developed and maintained the front end functionality of a web project using HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JQuery and Javascript.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER // INTERNSHIP

JULY 2015 - AUG 2015

STATE OIL COMPANY OF AZERBAİJAN (SOCAR)

Developed and designed an application for customers using JAVA and Android within a team working on Agile/Scrum environment.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER // INTERNSHIP

JULY 2014 - AUG 2014

WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

SEPT 2013 - MAY 2014

BESTCOMP GROUP

Builded the web application for employers of the company using C# and ASP.NET in a team with Agile/Scrum methodology.

GAZETEBILKENT

Developed and maintained the web pages of the largest student newspaper of Turkey, and designed posters for different events.



PROJECTS

GRADUATE ADMISSION TICKET SYSTEM

The goal of the graduate admission ticketing system is to transform the way the department organizes work around the selection and admission of grad students. The project is developed by a team of 7 people working with Agile - Scrum methodology to understand how to architect basic cloud based applications in AWS. Implemented event-driven stateless microservices as lambda functions, a custom authorization service (JSON Web Tokens), and implemented a UI by using AngularJS, Less and Bootstrap to consume the generic APIs that are created by following REST API guidelines.

THE BULLPEN

The Bullpen is a web application that allows users to keep track of baseball stats for a league and created by a team of three students. Used Express - Node.js web application framework as the back-end programming language to create REST API. AngularJS, Bootstrap3, and Less are used for front-end functionality. An open-source, NoSQL database MongoDB is also used for the project.

SPORTIFY

Sportify is an android application that improves the experience of attending sporting events by providing a platform for people to find others. The project is developed by a team of 7 people working with Agile - Scrum methodology. Used Java and various Object Oriented Design Patterns, and SQLite Database to store all information.

PHOTORENAMER

PhotoRenamer is a Java based application that allows a user to easily rename image files based on a set of tags. The user can choose a directory and view a list of all image files anywhere under that directory. When viewing an image, the user can select tags from the currently-existing tags, and the user can also add new tags and delete existing ones from the currently-existing ones. This allows the user to use their operating system to search for image files.

ELECTRON LIBRARY SYSTEM

Electron Library System developed to help local school libraries manage all paper works online. The project was based on C# and ASP.NET and developed by me. It is currently being used in one of twelve Turkish High School in Azerbaijan. The project won bronze medal in the programming category in International Infomatrix Olympiads in Romania in 2012.